Guide to the John Reesing papers, 1964-1982 MS0601.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
John Reesing papers
1964-1982
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Reesing, John
MS0601.UA
1.5 Linear Feet
John Palmer Reesing, Jr. (1920-91) was a Professor of English at The George Washington University. Materials in this collection include memos, course outlines, course descriptions, syllabi and articles. They range in date from 1964-82, and the provenance of this collection is not known, the old accession log listed it as being received in 1987.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Provenance of this collection is unknown.
Historical or Biographical Note
John Palmer Reesing, Jr. (1920-91) was a Professor of English at The George Washington University.Dr. Reesing was born September 15, 1920 in Gatesville, Texas. He earned his B.A. from Baylor University in 1941, his M.A. from Tulane University in 1942 and his Ph.D. from Harvard in 1954. He served in the Army during World War II, from 1942-46, and ended his service as a First Lieutenant.
Dr. Reesing came to GW in 1946 as an Instructor in English. In 1953 he left to teach at Oberlin College for one year and then returned to GW in 1954, retiring in 1988 and being conferred Emeritus status.He served as Chair of the English Department from 1963-70, and acting chair from 1972-73.
Dr. Reesing specialized in 17th century English literature and John Milton. He was the author of "Milton's Poetic Art" (1968), and a member of the Modern Language Association of America, the Renaissance Society of America, and International Association of University Professors of English. Professor Reesing died in 1991.
N.B. This history note was written in 2005
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include memos, course outlines, course descriptions, syllabi and articles. They range in date from 1964-82, and the provenance of this collection is not known, the old accession log listed it as being received in 1987.
English literature; Washington (D.C.); English; Reesing, John; George Washington University
- Ingraham, Alinda:In Adam's Room: The Son in Paradise Regained as Prelapsarian Man, 05/11/1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Report Schedules/Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- McCaudlish Report, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Undergraduate Major in English Literature, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- English Majors - info for, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- English 194 Syllabus, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Comedy 1693-1707 Timeline, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Comedy 1668-1676 Timeline, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Tragedy - Late 17th Century Outline, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Heroic Plays 1664-1677 Timeline, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- The Greater Lyric - Spenser to Dryden, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Post-Elizabethan Lyric, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Narrative Poetry, 1575-1700, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 2nd Half of the 14th Century, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- After Chaucer: Late Medieval Poets, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Elizabethan-Prose Fiction, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- English Drama to 1642, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Literary Evidence of English Reformation, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Humanists, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- The "Sidney" Years, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- 1598-1609, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Poetical Miscellanies, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- "Herbert's Naming" by Sibyl Lutz Severance, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- "Platonism" by Jon A. Quitslund, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Forum XIV (4), undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Materials to work on, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- English 126 Description, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
- English Course Descriptions, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Prodigals and Pilgrims: The American Revolution Against Patriarchal Authority, 1750-1800, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Class Outlines and Syllabi, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)